<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>webauthn on r4gus</title><link>https://r4gus.github.io/tags/webauthn/</link><description>Recent content in webauthn on r4gus</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>David P. Sugar</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2023 17:27:36 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://r4gus.github.io/tags/webauthn/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>FIDO2: everything perfect?</title><link>https://r4gus.github.io/posts/whats-the-plan/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2023 17:27:36 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://r4gus.github.io/posts/whats-the-plan/</guid><description>Around a year ago, I found myself captivated by the FIDO2 authentication protocol, also known as PassKey. The promises made by the FIDO Alliance, a consortium featuring tech giants like Microsoft, Google, and Apple, were compelling - envisioning a future where passwords become obsolete, replaced by a faster, easier, and more secure authentication system across all devices (see Passkeys).
If you&amp;rsquo;ve been keeping an eye on cybersecurity news, you&amp;rsquo;re likely familiar with the significant incidents stemming from phishing attacks.</description></item><item><title>FIDO2 - Passwortlose Authentifizierung</title><link>https://r4gus.github.io/posts/fido-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2022 10:42:53 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://r4gus.github.io/posts/fido-1/</guid><description>Die fido Alliance möchte mit dem FIDO2 Standard nicht weniger, als die Art, wie wir uns in unserem digitalen Alltag authentifizieren, zu revolutionieren. Versprochen wird eine einfach zu handhabende Lösung, die Passwörter, auf lange Sicht, vollkommen ablöst und dabei deutlich sicherer ist als herkömmliche Authentifizierungslösungen. An den meisten Leuten, die nicht den neuesten Tech-Trends folgen, dürft FIDO2 jedoch bisher unbemerkt vorbeigezogen sein. Wenn überhaupt, ist der Begriff YubiKey bekannt, bei welchem es sich wohl um den geläufigsten FIDO2 Authenticator handelt.</description></item></channel></rss>